Okay, so the first programmatic assessment was .value_counts on
好了 第一个编程评估是对病人表格中的姓和地址列
the surname and address column at the patient's table.
运行 .value_counts
Value counts is like a histogramming function
value_counts 是一种直方图函数
that returns the count of each unique value in that column.
返回的是该列中某个特定值的计数
And there are six last names of Doe as well as six addresses of 123 Main Street.
这里有六个病人姓 Doe 以及六个地址在 123 Main Street
I've got a hunch that these are duplicates which we can check using .duplicated.
我感觉这可能是因为重复 我们可以用 .duplicated 查看
This returns a boolean series which we then index patients with.
这样会返回我们可以用来索引病人的布尔数组
And, yeah, there are several John Doe's that live at 123 Main Street New York,
是的 这里有很多位 John Doe
New York, ZIP Code 12345.
都住在纽约 123 Main Street 邮编为12345
And there's more, johndoe@email.com.
还有很多的 johndoe@email.com
This reeks of duplicate default data.
这个明显是重复的默认数据
So how could this have happened.
这种情况是怎么发生的呢
This is probably because of some system conversion.
很有可能是因为一些系统更换
For example, say if the company that has
比如说 如果公司的数据库
this database switched from one software provider to another for their patient records.
从一个软件供应商转换至另外一个软件供应商 以进行病人记录
When converting from one system to another,
在从一个系统更换至另一个系统的过程中
you can often lose data and it becomes this default John Doe data or even corrupted data.
可能会丢失一些数据 然后出现默认的 John Doe 数据或者甚至损坏数据
This is a pretty common issue in health care data,
医护数据中这个问题非常普遍
especially because healthcare is known as not
因为大家都知道
being the most up-to-date in terms of technology.
医护行业的技术向来都不是最新的
So what's the appropriate data quality dimension for this one.
那这个问题的合适的数据质量维度是什么呢？
This is a validity issue.
这个是有效性问题
Recall that validity means not conforming to
之前说过 有效性问题
a defined schema and this schema is the real world schema this time.
是指不符合预先确定的当前真实世界的情况
It's very, very, very unlikely,
六位 John Doe
I'd say impossible that there are six
都住在纽约 123 Main Street
John Doe's that all live at 123 Main Street in New York,
使用同一个邮箱
New York with the same email.
这真的是非常不可能的事情
It's just not, this isn't happening.
这种事情不可能存在
So while this table or the database accepts these records,
虽然这个表格或数据库接受了这些记录
it's not valid in terms of the real world schema.
但就真实世界的情况而言 这些记录是无效的
John Doe might not even exist and realistically he probably doesn't.
John Doe 甚至可能都不存在 现实中很有可能是这样
So let's document that.
让我们记录下来
It'll be important to clean this because we don't want garbage data in our data set.
这个问题必须要解决 因为我们不希望数据集中有垃圾数据
This might mean removing these records or finding records that were lost,
也就是说 我们可能要移除这些记录 或者找到丢失的记录
but we'll deal with that later.
我们之后再来处理
Right now we're just assessing and writing down our observations.
现在我们只进行评估 并写下自己的观察结果
There's actually another data quality issue revealed by
通过 duplicated 实际上我们还可以发现另外一个数据质量问题
this duplicated method here and one offending record is this Jake Jacobson record.
这个 Jake Jacobson 的记录有些问题
You'll see that this duplicate actually has
你可以发现它的地址是重复的
address being duplicated as opposed to this record here,
与这条记录
or these two down here having NaN entries.
或者下面两条显示 NaN 条目的记录不一样
This means that two people in this patient's table have the same address,
也就意味着病人表格中有两个人地址是相同的
648 Old Dear Lane.
648 Old Dear Lane
I actually recall seeing
我记得之前我们在目测评估的时候
a Jacobson earlier in our visual assessment. Let's scroll back up.
看见过 Jacobson 我们向上滑动看看
Okay, here it is, Jacob Jacobson,
这里 Jacob Jacobson
648 Old Dear Lane and also a Jake Jacobson,
648 Old Dear Lane 然后还有一个 Jake Jacobson
which is a record we saw in the duplicated results below.
这就是我们在 duplicated 结果中看到的记录
So this seems like there's two records for one person.
这看上去是一个人的两条记录
This extra record and extra patient ID was created because this nickname was used.
之所以另外创建了一条记录和一个病人 ID 是因为使用了昵称
Basically Jake Jacobson came back twice and the person that was in charge of creating
应该是 Jake Jacobson 来过两次
these patient records accidentally put Jake in again
而负责创建病人记录的人又另外记录了一条 Jake 的信息
because they didn't recognize that he was already in the database.
因为没发现数据库中已经有他的信息了
This use of nicknames creating duplicates is a very famous issue in
使用昵称重复创建记录是医护行业中
healthcare data and it's an issue that costs
非常常见的问题
healthcare companies and hospitals tons of money every year.
每一年医护公司和医院都要耗重金来解决这个问题
There's a handy link illustrating this in the notes below
如果你想了解更多内容
this video if you'd like to read more.
可以查看视频下方说明中的链接
So this is actually a validity issue currently.
所以这是一个有效性问题
Though it's pretty easy to confuse as a consistency issue.
虽然很容易误以为它是一致性问题
Consistency being two ways of referring to the same thing,
用两种方式称呼同一件事物
Jake and Jacob Jacobson.
Jake 和 Jacob Jacobson 这种一致性问题
So while this is valid in terms of the specific table schema,
虽然它对于表格来说是有效的
there's no duplicate patient ID i.e.
没有重复的病人 ID
Jake Jacobson has 30,
比如说 Jake Jacobson 的病人 ID 是 30
Jacob has 25 for patient ID.
Jacob 是 25
But this is invalid in terms of the real world schema.
但是就真实世界情况而言它是无效的
This isn't two people, it's one person.
因为没有两个人 他只是一个人
There are two records in the patients table while there should be one.
病人表中出现了两条记录 而实际上只需要一条
When deleting one of the duplicates,
在删除其中一个复制内容时
if we delete the wrong one,
如果我们错误地删除了一条内容
then we'll create a consistency issue between multiple tables.
这样就会造成多个表格之间的一致性问题
For example, if Jacob Jacobson is in the treatments table as well while
比如说 治疗表中是 Jacob Jacobson
this Jake Jacobson is only in patients and we delete the Jacob Jacobson record,
而病人表中只留下了 Jake Jacobson 我们删掉了 Jacob Jacobson
that would be a inconsistent representation across tables,
这样就会造成各个表格之间的不一致问题
while still having only one record per one person,
但是每个人只留下了一条记录
so it's valid but inconsistent.
这样它是有效的 但却是不一致的
That's not what we have right now though.
但这不是我们眼下的问题
Right now we have two ways of referring to
现在我们是有两种方式找到两条记录
two records when there should only be one record.
而实际上只应该存在一条记录
That last part is the invalid part.
最后一部分是无效的
There are actually a few more of these nickname duplicated patients.
其实这里还有其他昵称重复的病人
Sandy Taylor and Sandra Taylor,
Sandy Taylor 和 Sandra Taylor
living at 2476 Fulton Street.
住在 2476 Fulton Street
Then also Pat and Patrick Gersten that lives at 2778 North Avenue.
Pat 和 Patrick Gersten 住在 2778 North Avenue
And as always we document this.
同样地 我们把这些记录下来
Okay, so let's move on to the next programmatic assessment
现在我们继续对病人表中的体重列
on the weight column in the patient's table.
进行编程评估
And the minimum value is 48.8 pounds.
最低值是 48.8 磅
This seems not possible for a living human,
对于一个大活人来说 这不可能
so this is definitely at least inaccurate, maybe invalid.
至少是不准确的 也可能是无效的
But actually if we think a bit deeper,
但如果我们更深一步地思考
we'll see that it's actually neither of those.
会发现两者都不是
This is actually a consistency issue in disguise.
真实情况是 这其实是一致性问题
48.8 is actually kilograms instead of pounds,
48.8 其实是公斤 而不是磅
which we can check by corroborating the height and
我们可以通过名为 Zaitseva 这位病人的
BMI entries for this patient who has the last name Zaitseva.
身高和 BMI 进行验证
So 2.20462 is the conversion factor between kilograms and pounds
2.20462 是公斤和磅的转化系数
and 703 times weight in pounds divided by height squared is the BMI calculation formula.
703 乘以体重磅数 除以身高平方 这是 BMI 计算公式
And with 48.8 kilograms converted to pounds,
把 48.8 公斤转换为磅
this yields about 19.1 BMI,
得到的结果是 19.1 BMI
which if we checked the actual BMI in the data set is
我们检查数据集中的 BMI
exactly the same or close to it before rounding.
与这个数字一样 或者如果在四舍五入之前 与这个数字相近
So here the 48.8 is actually right,
所以这个 48.8 也是对的
it's just off in units.
但是单位不对
So this is actually a consistency issue.
所以实际上是一致性问题
This was caused by a simple misunderstanding or
这一般是因为录入数据的人
just a simple oversight by whoever was entering this data.
有表格有误解或者疏忽造成的
Again, this is important to clean because we need to report the average metrics,
这个是非常需要解决的 因为我们需要
like weight, height, and more,
为临床试验的每个治疗组
in terms of each treatment arm of the clinical trial.
上报平均指标比如体重、身高这些
Auralin and Novodra and there's some documentation for this.
这里是问题的记录
And Okay now the last programmatic assessments,
好了 现在是最后的编程评估
the .isnull methods on the Auralin and Novodra columns in the treatment's table.
对治疗表中 Auralin 和 Novodra 列运行 .isnull
This bit of code within the sum parentheses.
应该放至在 sum 的圆括号内
This returns a Boolean series which is
这样会根据条目是否为空值
true or false based on whether or not each entry is null or not.
返回一些说明真假的布尔数组
And Boolean series can be summed as a whole.
可以对整个布尔数组进行求和
True being one, false being zero.
真的为 1 假的为 0
So this output suggests that there are
这个结果的意思就是
zero null entries for both the Auralin and Novodra columns.
Auralin 和 Novodra 列中都没有空值条目
But that shouldn't be the case, right?
但情况其实不是这样的 对吧？
If we scroll up to our treatment's visual assessment,
如果我们向上滑动至对治疗表的目测评估
these entries with the dashes should be null or at least represented as such.
这些破折号的条目其实是空值 或至少应该表达为空值
This reveals a common error in multiple data sets,
这反应了多个数据集中的常见错误
not just healthcare data sets.
不仅是医护数据集
Misrepresenting missing values is something else,
即将缺失的值表达为其它东西
like a dash or a slash or NaN
比如说破折号、斜杠或 NaN (不适用)
or none for example, the text None.
或者文本 None (空)
And if you scroll down to our info programmatic assessment,
如果下拉至我们的 info 编程评估
the Auralin and Novodra columns are objects or strings.
会看到 Auralin 和 Novodra 列为对象或字符串
These dashes aren't picked up as null or non-values.
这些破折号就不被认为是空值或没有值
Why is this important to document and later clean?
为什么这个问题这么重要 我们需要现在记录下来 之后解决呢？
Calculations in Pandas and spreadsheet applications even behave
Pandas 和电子表格应用中的计算
a certain way based on how these null values are represented.
通常基于如何表达空值
In Pandas for example,
比如说 在 Pandas 中
since each column or series can only have one data type,
每一列或每一个数组只有一种数据类型
we wouldn't be able to convert these dosage columns to
我们不能将这些剂量的列转为值数据类型
a numerical data type to perform mean and standard deviation calculations,
再进行平均值和标准偏差计算
which we'll need to report in the clinical trial findings.
用来上报我们的临床试验发现
But also nulls are important.
但是再次强调 在 Google Sheets 或电子表格应用中
Again, if you're working in something like Google Sheets or a spreadsheet application.
空值也很重要
So spreadsheet applications allow multiple data types in one column,
电子表格应用一列中可以有多种数据类型存在
like this is allowed 40-50 dash dash dash 60.
比如这里 允许使用 40、50、破折号、破折号、破折号、60
With this cell this cell and this cell 40-50-60 still being treated as
而这几个单元格 40、50、60 依然被认为是整数
integers while these dash dash dash cells are treated as text variables.
而这几个破折号单元格被认为是文本变量
This is important because say if you wanted to
这一点很重要
calculate standard deviation for this column,
如果你想要使用函数 STDEVA
this example column, the function STDEVA.
计算这一列的标准偏差
This calculates standard deviation but sets the text
计算时 会把文本值
values aka the dash dash dash to zero.
也就是这里的破折号 设为零
If these were missing values you'd get a different calculation,
而如果这里没有内容 得到的计算结果就不同
which I'll show you right here actually.
我这里展示给你看
So the correct representation of nulls is important.
所以空值的正确表达很重要
So let's document that.
让我们记录下来
This is a validity issue because nulls should be nulls, not text
这个是有效性问题 因为空值应该为空值 而不是文本